Guide to the Jeffrey Leeds Collection on NYU Glee Club MC.265
New York University Archives
Jeffrey Leeds Collection on NYU Glee Club
1936-2000
1964-1968
New York University Archives
Leeds, Jeffrey
MC.265
1.5 Linear Feet in 1 manuscript box and 1 oversize flat box
3 Cassettes audiocassettes
3 sound discs (cd)
Jeffrey Leeds is an actor, producer, and alumnus of New York University with a Bachelor of Arts in Psychology and Master of Science in Public Administration. He was a member of the NYU Glee Club and the original Vice President of the NYU Choral Arts Alumni Club. The Jeffrey Leeds Papers (dated 1936-2000) consist of materials created and collected by Jeffrey Leeds documenting his participation in the New York University Glee Club and other aspects of the university's musical organizations. Materials include performance programs, audio recordings, photographs, and other ephemera. The collection also includes Leeds' Glee Club blazer.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Jeffrey Leeds in July 2016; the accession number associated with this gift is 2016.026.
Arrangement
This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor.
Biographical / Historical
Jeffrey Leeds is an actor and producer, and as of 2016 is the President of the All Out Arts Board of Directors. Leeds is an alumnus of New York University with a Bachelor of Arts in Psychology and Master of Science in Public Administration. He was a member of the NYU Glee Club and the original Vice President of the NYU Choral Arts Alumni Club.
Content Description
The Jeffrey Leeds Papers (dated 1936-2000) consist of materials created and collected by Jeffrey Leeds documenting his participation in the New York University Glee Club and other aspects of the university's musical organizations. Materials include performance programs, audio recordings, photographs, and other ephemera. The collection also includes Leeds' Glee Club blazer and 11 photographs taken by Arthur Smithline documenting student musical group activities in the 1930s.
Custodial History
Photographs taken by Arthur Smithline were donated to E. Jon Revere by Suzanne Smithline Manion, Smithline's daughter, and her husband Glenn Manion. Revere, a former conductor of the NYU Glee Club, later gave the photographs to Jeffrey Leeds to be added to his collection.
Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
Access CDs for sound recordings in the collection are available by appointment for reading room viewing and listening only.
Student activities.; Glee clubs; New York University. Glee Club
- NYU Glee Club Scrapbook, 1964-1968; cuid393 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- NYU Alumni Student Lounge Furniture Plan, 1987-09-03; cuid395 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Performance Programs, 1973-2000; cuid396 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- History of the NYU Glee Club, undated; cuid397 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Photographs by Arthur Smithline, circa 1936-1937; cuid398 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Performance Photograph with Annotations, undated; cuid399 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- New York University Glee Club 110th Anniversary Concert Including "A Tribute to Alfred M. Greenfield" Audiocassette, 1983-05-07; cuid329 (Box 1, Cassette cuid329, E-records nyuarchives_MC265, E-records cuid329, Box Shared University Archives 119, Disk 18, Disk 19)
  Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
  1/8" audiocassette, 94 min.
- New York University 125th Anniversary Choral Concert Audiocassette, 1998-04-25; cuid330 (Box 1, Cassette cuid330, E-records nyuarchives_MC265, E-records cuid330, Box Shared University Archives 119, Disk 20, Disk 21)
  1/8" audiocassette, 99 min.
- New York University Glee Club Varsity Quartet "The Subway" Vinyl Record, 1941; cuid331 (Box 1, Disc cuid331, E-records nyuarchives_MC265, E-records cuid331, Box Shared University Archives 119, Disk 22)
  Vinyl record, 6 min.
- Glee Club Blazer, 1964-1968; cuid394 (Box 2)